A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Advanced Medical Fellowships, SG 1, Series 3 FA275
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Advanced Medical Fellowships, SG 1, Series 3
1937-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA275
27.88 Cubic Feet 71 boxes
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement note
This series is arranged in 5 subseries:
Subseries 1 Administrative Files
Subseries 2 Fellowships and Awards in the Health Field
Subseries 3 Foreign Fellowships
Subseries 4 Institutional Block Grants
Subseries 5 Special Awards in Support of Creative Scholarship
Biographical/Historical note
The Commonwealth Fund was established in 1918 with an endowment of $10 million from Mrs. Stephen V. Harkness for "benevolent, religious, educational and like purposes." The early grants supported a variety of programs while generally promoting welfare, especially child welfare. Several grants were made in the field of medical research, but the Board of Directors decided in 1920 that this field was already sufficiently supported by other philanthropic organizations.
Despite this decision, by the mid-1920s the chief interest of the Fund had become public health, including mental hygiene, community health, rural hospitals, medical research, and medical education. Other grant areas included war relief, educational and legal research, child welfare, and international medical fellowships.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IX; IV 4B 4
Other Finding Aids note
A three-part card file index to the fellowships is available for researcher use.
One: An alphabetical file of all fellowship recipients, regardless of the type of fellowship. The cards for the letter "A" have been lost. Two: fellowships indexed by medical school. Three: foreign fellowships indexed by country.
Scope and Contents note
Fellowships are an integral part of the Commonwealth Fund's history, and continually supported the varied public health, mental hygiene, and rural hospital programs of the CF. The advanced medical fellowships were first awarded in 1937, and although they primarily aided medical school teachers and research workers, individuals in other areas of health work also received financial assistance. About twenty fellowships per year were granted during 1950-1959, many of which entailed interdisciplinary studies, and by 1965 well over sixty fellowships were awarded yearly.
The granting of "Special Fellowships for Selected Foreign Students" started in June 1947 with an initial appropriation of $50,000. These foreign fellowships were suspended on February 20, 1953, when the CF Board removed them from the published program of the Fund. Nonetheless, occasional awards were made in cases where the individual was known to the Fund or if the project coincided with Fund interests. The awards were to be made from accumulated balances from the general fellowship budget. The CF Board, however, reversed its position on May 26, 1955, and restored to the Fellowship Committee the power to award foreign fellowships. Many of the later foreign fellows were recommended by the ASME and the SFME. An initial appropriation of $50,000 was included in this action. Beginning in 1956, "Special Awards in Support of Creative Scholarship" allowed outstanding teachers or research workers to spend a year or two free from departmental obligations.
The advanced medical fellowships covered four basic areas of interest: 1) aid to candidates seeking advanced or interdisciplinary training; 2) assistance in the development of new or neglected fields of activity in health matters; 3) assistance to programs of institutions or organizations active in disciplines of interest to the CF; 4) grants to provide time-off for mature and creative scholars of acknowledged ability.
Initially the Commonwealth Fund Board of Directors, on the basis of staff recommendations, awarded the fellowships, but starting October 1947, the Board made an overall program appropriation and the staff selected the recipients. Beginning in 1950 a fellowship committee, chaired by Roderick Heffron, chose the fellows, contingent upon the approval of the Commonwealth Fund's president.
A number of British medical school teachers also received fellowships which enabled them to study at U.S. institutions. During the first twenty-five years of the program, 377 American and 112 foreign fellowships were granted. In addition, several large "Block Grants" figured prominently in the fellowship program: The National League for Nursing, Inc. (Fellowship Program for Advanced Education, 1955-1961), provided financial assistance to enable competent nurses to complete master's or doctor's degrees; The Provident Medical Associates of Chicago, renamed in 1952 National Medical Fellowships, Inc., financed improved education for black physicians; and during 1961-1964 The Population Council, Inc. received funding for medical and biological fellowships. The Population Council material is located in box 285 of the Commonwealth Fund Archives Grants Series.
In addition, The Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine (Exchange Fellowship Program to Assist Selected Foreign Medical Schools) and the University of Rochester School of Medicine and Dentistry received grants from the Commonwealth Fund to help underwrite their foreign exchange programs. Universities associated with The Johns Hopkins program include the American University of Beirut, Cayetano Heredia University in Lima, Peru, and the University of Ibadan, Nigeria. Only one foreign institution, The University of the West Indies, was awarded a "Block Grant."
Dr. Heffron's retirement in September 1966 signaled major revisions in the Fund's fellowship program. The Board of Directors reduced the 1966-1967 fiscal year appropriation to $350,000, down from the previous allocation of $550,000. Not surprisingly, the number of fellows dropped from seventy-eight to thirty for the same time span. In May of 1967 the Board voted to end the formal fellowship program, but agreed to maintain some financial assistance through a small discretionary fund awarded on an informal basis. The number of awards continually declined, nineteen during 1967-1968 and ten during 1968-1969, and no new appropriations were granted until the 1968-1969 fiscal year. In May 1970, however, the Board decided to cancel this appropriation and restored the remaining monies to the CF's general fund.
The advanced medical fellowships are complete for the years 1937 to 1970.
Other Finding Aids
Other available finding aids describing the Commonwealth Fund records include:
FA247 Commonwealth Fund Harkness House drawings
FA276 Commonwealth Fund records, Annual Reports, SG 1, Series 4
FA277 Commonwealth Fund records, Archives/Library, SG 1, Series 5
FA278 Commonwealth Fund records, Austrian Program, SG 1, Series 6
FA279 Commonwealth Fund records, Board of Directors, SG 1, Series 7
FA280 Commonwealth Fund records, Capital Grants, SG 1, Series 8
FA281 Commonwealth Fund records, Child Health Demonstrations, SG 1, Series 9
FA282 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Community Clinics, SG 1, Series 10
FA283 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Health Studies, SG 1, Series 11
FA284 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12
FA285 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Publications, SG 1, Series 13
FA286 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Rural Hospitals, SG 1, Series 14
FA287 Commonwealth Fund records, Educational Research, SG 1, Series 15
FA288 Commonwealth Fund records, English Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 16
FA289 Commonwealth Fund records, Finance Committee, SG 1, Series 17
FA290 Commonwealth Fund records, Grants, SG 1, Series 18
FA291 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Family, SG 1, Series 19
FA292 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, SG 1, Series 20
FA428 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, Fellows Reports, SG 1, Series 20A
FA293 Commonwealth Fund records, Institute for Child Guidance, SG 1, Series 21
FA294 Commonwealth Fund records, Interface Program, SG 1, Series 22
FA295 Commonwealth Fund records, Legal Research Program, SG 1, Series 23
FA296 Commonwealth Fund records, Living at Home Program, SG 1, Series 24
FA297 Commonwealth Fund records, Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 25
FA298 Commonwealth Fund records, Miscellaneous - unprocessed
FA299 Commonwealth Fund records, Personnel - unprocessed
FA300 Commonwealth Fund records, Pilgrim Trust, SG 1, Series 28
FA301 Commonwealth Fund records, Program for the Prevention of Delinquency, SG 1, Series 29
FA302 Commonwealth Fund records, Reference Files, SG 1, Series 30
FA303 Commonwealth Fund records, Reports of the General Director, SG 1, Series 31
FA304 Commonwealth Fund records, Treasurer, SG 1, Series 32
FA305 Commonwealth Fund records, Turndown Lists, SG 1, Series 33 - unprocessed
FA306 Commonwealth Fund records, Vertical File (R. Fitz), SG 1, Series 34 - unprocessed
FA307 Commonwealth Fund records, Visual Materials, SG 1, Series 35
FA389 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Historical Files, SG 1, Series 1
FA390 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Officers Files, SG 1, Series 2
FA429 Commonwealth Fund records, President, Margaret E. Mahoney, SG 2, Series 1
FA430 Commonwealth Fund records, Book Program, SG 2, Series 2
Mental health; Medicine -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; War relief; Child psychology; Child welfare; New York (N.Y.); Child mental health; Public health; New York (State); United States; Public welfare; Medical research; Medicine, Rural; Legal research; Medical education; Law; Legal issues; Education, Rural; Hygiene
- Administrative Files, 1945-1970; 1
  Arrangement note
  The material in this subseries is filed chronologically.
  Scope and Contents note
  This subseries contains Board of Directors Reports, Fellowship Committee Minutes, interoffice memoranda, and general correspondence.
  - Australian Medical Fellowships - Correspondence and Memoranda, July 24, 1945-July 23, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors Reports and Appropriations (Domestic Fellowships), October 23, 1947-May 16, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors Reports and Appropriations (Domestic Fellowships), May 8, 1958-May 10, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors Reports and Appropriations (Domestic Fellowships), January 16, 1963-May 5, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors Reports and Appropriations (Foreign Fellowships), June 12, 1947-July 14, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors Reports and Appropriations (Foreign Fellowships), October 14, 1948-May 12, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors Reports and Appropriations (Foreign Fellowships), May 11, 1961-May 11, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors Reports and Appropriations (Special Awards for Creative Scholarship), November 17, 1955 to May 8, 1958; May 26, 1969 to May 26, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fellowship Committee Minutes, November 12, 1963-October 29, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fellowship Committee Minutes, March 10, 1965-October 29, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fellowship Committee Minutes, March 14, 1966-September 13, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Fellowships and Awards in the Health Field, 1933-1978; 2
  The material in this subseries is arranged alphabetically by fellow. The material within each fellow's file is arranged chronologically.
  This subseries consists of correspondence, financial data, and reports.
  - Acheson, Roy Malcolm, March 11, 1966-July 10, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Adams, John M., July 29, 1963-December 28, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Adams, Raymond A., January 12, 1950-September 16, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Aldrich, C. Knight, October 17, 1961-September 7, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Alexander, Benjamin, August 9, 1962-April 11, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Alger, Ian, April 16, 1951-May 12, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Allison, Fred Jr., January 19, 1965-September 22, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Alway, Robert Hamilton, December 17, 1963-October 12, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - American Academy of Pediatrics, November 26, 1963-Feruary 29, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Anderson, Donald G., December 27, 1963-February 17, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Anderson, John A., April 23, 1961-February 18, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Anderson, Richard W., September 27, 1962-December 28, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Andrews, William H., January 11, 1949-November 18, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Angrist, Alfred, September 22, 1965-April 26, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Armstrong, Wallace D., November 16, 1937 to March 1, 1941; February 1, 1949 to April 18, 1955; August 27, 1958 to August 15, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Arnold, John H., January 28, 1955-May 22, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Atkins, Elisha, January 24, 1962-August 14, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Austin, James H., March 29, 1961-May 18, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Austin, James H., March 29, 1961-May 18, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Austrian, Robert, August 18, 1959-September 13, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Baker, Richard F., November 6, 1956-January 28, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Balch, Henry H., March 5, 1946-April 21, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Baldwin, DeWitt, November 29, 1950-March 13, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Bales, Robert F., February 25, 1952-November 6, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Ball, Eric G., August 29, 1959 to January 25, 1960; December 12, 1962 to February 17, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Bancroft, Huldah, January 17, 1938-February 21, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Barger, A. Clifford, May 12, 1959-January 8, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Barnett, Henry L., June 3, 1963-June 13, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Barnett, Thomas B., April 29, 1965-May 16, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Barron, Almen L., May 28, 1963-September 28, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Barzd, Vera, July 14, 1949-September 12, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Beeson, Paul B., January 15, 1965-May 28, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Beierwaltes, William H., October 22, 1965-November 28, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Beierwaltes, William H., October 22, 1965-November 28, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Beierwaltes, William H., October 22, 1965-November 28, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Benditt, Earl P., January 27, 1964-November 30, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Bennett, Leslie L., July 3, 1947-July 15, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Benton, Robert S., March 22, 1958-February 19, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Bergner, Grace E., January 6, 1945-December 3, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Berne, Robert M., October 14, 1958 to November 7, 1960; March 22, 1965 to September 2, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Bernheimer, Alan W., May 1, 1959 to September 22, 1960; February 7, 1966 to April 4, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Berryhill, Walter Reece, December 11, 1959-August 26, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Berson, Robert C., June 12, 1962-October 3, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Berwald, James F., March 24, 1950-June 20, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Blake, John B., December 31, 1953-May 20, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Bland, John H., May 1, 1958-December 15, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Blankenhorn, David H., June 24, 1963-September 14, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Blankenship, Charles F., July 6, 1962-October 4, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Boder, Elena, March 10, 1961-September 7, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Bogdonoff, Morton D., December 4, 1962-October 24, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Boles, William M., October 31, 1939-October 20, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Bridges, William C., March 13, 1944-February 18, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Brooks, Frank P., February 10, 1955-October 23, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Brown, Albert B., September 4, 1953-January 27, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Brown, Ellen, February 3, 1944-October 6, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Brown, Kenneth T., January 29, 1963-November 8, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Browneller, Ellsworth R., April 15, 1955-February 3, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Bruce, Robert Arthur, November 9, 1964-July 8, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Bruner, Jerome S., November 2, 1949-May 10, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Buddingh, G. John, February 1, 1938-June 2, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Bunker, John Philip, July 19, 1965-July 17, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Bunnell, Ivan Lee, April 29, 1959-April 21, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Bunting, Henry, April 12, 1946-May 16, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Burch, George E., October 7, 1938 to August 19, 1941; June 27, 1961 to July 27, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Burnett, Charles H., September 22, 1959-June 4, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Buxton, C. Lee, December 9, 1959-April 24, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Campbell, Jean, March 17, 1954-September 8, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Carnes, William H., September 19, 1962-April 13, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Carter, George Herbert, September 22, 1965-September 25, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Catchpole, Hubert R., July 29, 1941-January 14, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Caudill, William, July 8, 1953-November 21, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Cavelti, Philip A., May 6, 1942-February 26, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Chandler, Arthur B., January 26, 1961-April 11, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Chaplin, Hugh, Jr., January 25, 1961-September 28, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Charalampous, Frixos C., April 28, 1960-October 22, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Chargaff, Erwin, January 27, 1965-December 9, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Chase, Harold F., October 31, 1947-June 15, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Childs, Barton, January 31, 1952-September 19, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Christian, Howard J., April 19, 1963-November 9, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Christopherson, William Martin, March 1, 1961-December 15, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Clark, Duncan W., November 27, 1939 to January 26, 1942; January 25, 1961 to September 7, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Clark, Duncan W., November 27, 1939 to January 26, 1942; January 25, 1961 to September 7, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Clement, David H., October 3, 1945-May 5, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Cleveland, Anne Stack, August 9, 1960-September 21, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Cohen, Jerome, March 4, 1963-January 14, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Cohen, Sanford I., September 13, 1965-May 22, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Cohen, Sanford I. (Report), April 1967 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Cohen, Sanford I. (Report), April 1967 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Cohen, Seymour S., November 19, 1965-December 13, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Cohn, Roy B., December 19, 1961-July 17, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - University of Colorado (Drs. Jensen, Liggett, Sudan, Dixon and Florio), February 1, 1949-November 18, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Comroe, Julius H., November 6, 1937-December 13, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Conn, Hadlkey L., Jr., April 28, 1969-August 20, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Cooper, Donald B., November 12, 1966-March 25, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Corcoran, John W., August 26, 1963-April 27, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - Coye, Robert D., February 28, 1964-February 12, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - Craddock, William E., July 26, 1965-April 21, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 108)
  - Craig, Albert B., Jr., May 6, 1963-February 3, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - Craige, Ernest, March 9, 1962-October 1, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Crandall, Paul Herbert, November 9, 1964-June 28, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Crawford, John D., October 11, 1948 to July 2, 1951; November 12, 1957 to April 19, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - Creger, William P., August 24, 1962-November 1, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - Crispell, Kenneth R., November 4, 1948-July 16, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - Cumming, John, November 13, 1951-May 14, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 115)
  - Curtin, James A., February 1, 1956-April 10, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 116)
  - Dallam, Richard D., July 24, 1965-March 25, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Daniels, Oscar L., October 2, 1948-March 6, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 118)
  - Davidson, Gerald E., November 10, 1953-October 7, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 119)
  - Davie, Earl W., February 19, 1964-May 23, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 120)
  - Davis, Bernard D., August 3, 1967-January 27, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - Davis, Robert P., March 24, 1964-July 7, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 122)
  - Dawson, James R., Jr., September 23, 1940-May 25, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 123)
  - Deane, Helen W., July 1, 1963-September 7, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Delorme, Edmund J., July 26, 1947-December 9, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - Derrick, Walter A., September 10, 1940-December 11, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 126)
  - Deuschle, Kurt W., February 9, 1965-July 27, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - Deuschle, Kurt W., February 9, 1965-July 27, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 128)
  - Deuschle, Kurt W., February 9, 1965-July 27, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - Deuschle, Kurt W., February 9, 1965-July 27, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - Deuschle, Kurt W., February 9, 1965-July 27, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - Diamond, Louis K., April 21, 1966-October 15, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - Dickes, Robert, October 8, 1940 to November 2, 1942; September 20, 1950 to December 8, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 133)
  - Dingle, John H., February 10, 1965-August 4, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 134)
  - Donnell, George N., July 2, 1959-February 18, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Douglas, Gordon W., March 1, 1968-April 29, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 136)
  - Dreyfus, Edward G., June 29, 1951-October 17, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 137)
  - Dripps, Robert, Jr., November 1, 1939 to September 22, 1941; November 20, 1963 to April 9, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 138)
  - Duff, Ivan Francis, July 27, 1962-February 15, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 139)
  - Duff, Ivan Francis, July 27, 1962-February 15, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 140)
  - Dunihue, Fred W., March 18, 1963-February 9, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 141)
  - Durivage, Jacques, September 1, 1947-April 30, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - Eckenhoff, James E., March 10, 1961-July 8, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 143)
  - Edelman, I. S., September 10, 1964-December 12, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 144)
  - Eder, Howard A., November 12, 1963-March 8, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - Eisenberg, Eugene, April 29, 1965-January 17, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 146)
  - Eldred, Earl, October 27, 1958-October 1, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 147)
  - Elkin, Milton, January 18, 1962-June 10, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 148)
  - Engley, Frank B., Jr., November 23, 1964-January 18, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 149)
  - Epstein, Franklin H., June 13, 1963-June 17, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 150)
  - Epstein, Herman T., June 21, 1963-February 9, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - Epstein, Wallace V., August 24, 1964-September 19, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 152)
  - Farah, Alfred E., September 7, 1961-November 26, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 153)
  - Featherstone, Robert M., April 9, 1964-October 18, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 154)
  - Fernandez-Lopez, Carlos, October 11, 1962-August 27, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 155)
  - Ferrebee, Joseph W., May 27, 1955 to October 11, 1957; March 14, 1958 to September 2, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 156)
  - Fink, Bernard R., June 15, 1959-June 11, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 157)
  - Fischer, Harry W., September 26, 1963-March 11, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 158)
  - Fishman, Alfred P., December 2, 1963-March 21, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 159)
  - Fitch, Frank Wesley, January 6, 1964-September 21, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 160)
  - Fitzgerald, Patrick James, March 9, 1959-June 14, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 161)
  - Fitzgerald, Thomas B., July 18, 1957-January 11, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 162)
  - Flach, Frederic, October 11, 1951-February 4, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 163)